Pankaj Sharma / Chief Engineer

Remarkably knowledgeable experienced engineer in construction, renovation and pre-opening of hotel/Resort with over 12 years of experience in ensuring proper operation, maintenance and repair of hotels/resorts. Physical plant to support the goal of guest satisfaction, cost control and profitability. Overseeing and participating in the hotel's overall preventive maintenance program and ensuring that the quality and condition of all room amenities, equipment and public areas exceeds company and guest expectations



M: +211923534439 E: Pankaj.ncth@yahoo.com D.O.B: 01/02/1989 Add: Juba, South Sudan

Work Experience: 12 years+

Pyramid Continental Hotel

June 2022 – Present

Chief Engineer

Juba, South Sudan

Responsible for the operation, maintenance and repair of the entire hotel facility, including equipment, tools and facilities to ensure guest service and sustainability standards are achieved and maintained throughout the hotel. Manage duties and functions as it relates to decision making, organizing, planning, controlling, communicating and directing the Engineering department.

- Report Directly to General Manager
- Supervise over all operations with Engineering team toward 100% operability of all VRV HVAC, Diesel Generators with ATS and synchronised system, RO PLANT, SOLAR HEATER, VRF water pumps, Fire Pumps kitchen and laundry equipment
- Completion of all routine maintenance on public spaces, meeting rooms, outlets, back of the house spaces and grounds. Assigns and verifies completion of all repairs, replacement, and renovation projects to offices and employee work areas.
- Adhere to all corporate required purchasing policies and controls, to include all outside contractor bids, budgets and schedules.
- Maintain effective energy management and preventative maintenance programs, conducting special training for other operating departments on the safe and effective use of equipment and energy in the hotel.
- Maintain appropriate supply of materials and equipment to carry out the normal day-to-day operating and maintenance requirements of the hotel.
- Maintain organized and efficient administrative and filing systems within Property Operations for the timely and accurate handling of correspondence, reports, requisitions for purchase, and other administrative requirements of the department.
- Maintain a well-defined, and organized system within the shop for the inventory maintenance, and storage of all tools, products, materials, and equipment necessary to execute the required activities of the department.
- Immediately available to report to the hotel in the event of any hotel emergency which necessitates the skills and expertise of the Chief Engineer. By example such emergencies
- · Obtain necessary licenses and permit for installing, removing, and repairing physical building structures
- Address complaints from guests and ensure no such problems occur in the future

The Blowfish Group

July 2019 – June 2022

Group Maintenance Manager

Lagos, Nigeria

- Group Maintenance Manager of two hotels, staff Accommodations, 2-night club, 6 restaurants, Supermarket and central laundry of the Blowfish Group
- Ensure general engineering operations of hotel are intact and functioning adequately for no operational failures
- Since the hotel is almost 25 yrs. old; make sure maintenance team is more proactive than
 reactive to manage the engineering unexpected emergencies and general failures are
 handled well in timely manner; so that guest services are not hampered.
- Part of hotel goes into ongoing renovation, which was being planned to continue the project work while hotel remain in operations as well renovations are also continued while
- Led the team of 25 employees including an electric engineer and 2 supervisors; interview, schedule, train and coach, recommend performance review, resolve problems and recommend discipline as appropriate
- Maintained HT/LT Panels, Transformer (3 x 300 KVA), 4 Diesel Generators (400KVA, 350KV,300KVA and 200 KVA), Water treatment system, Firefighting system, Fire alarm system and HVAC

Sandies Baobab Beach Resort - Preopening

Chief Engineer

October 2018 – March 2019 **Zanzibar Island, Tanzania**

- Pre-opening of 105 Villas including Restaurants, Pool, SPA, offices and staff accommodation
- Be a part of testing and commissioning of HVAC, transformer 350 KVA, distribution LV rooms including LV/HV controls and Diesel generator capacity of 500KVA with ATS control system, WTP system and fire alarm systems.
- Snag-Resnag of plants and machinery and guest rooms as per Hotel Operating Procedure (SOP)
- Daily coordinate with Project consultant and contractors for major product defects
- Make sure the plants, building construction and fire and life safety product installation and functionally working under civil defense guidelines and regulation.
- Increased efficiency by implementing H&S standards, reviewed engineering drawing and developed pre-opening P&L and R&M budgets.
- Established Sandies Hospitality Quality Management system to effectively define and document procedure within the company by designing SOPs and Developing FM training modules
- Built a team from scratch to a professional engineering team

National Corporation tourism and hotels

Assistant Chief Engineer

Oct. 2016 – Sept. 2018 **Abu Dhabi. U.A.E**

(Property of 850 apartment Rooms- 3 meeting Rooms – 2 Swimming pools – 7 Water Features - 5
Transformers Oil Type – 15 Walk-in Fridges & Freezers -200 Kitchen Esg. – 2 Outlets - - 50Pumps, 3 Elevators & Laundry)

- Perform routine maintenance to determine damages, repairs and replacements.
- Support in developing preventive maintenance and energy conservation programs.
- Plan, coordinate and execute renovation projects.
- Assist in employee recruiting, training, performance evaluation and promotion activities.
- Ensure that building structures and all mechanical and electrical systems are in good and safe conditions.
- Create a master vender and contact list built on establishing strong working relationships.
- Ensure that engineering team uses equipment safely and efficiently to avoid accidents.
- Assist in managing all expenses within the allotted budget.

Doubletree by Hilton Resort & Spa-Pre opening

General Maintenance Supervisor/Acting Assistant Chief Engineer

Nov. 2013 – Sept. 2016

Marjan Island, Ras Al Khaimah, U.A.E

(Property of 723 rooms including 338 villas - 3 meeting Rooms -4 Air cooled Chillers -4-Cooling Tower 32 AHU - 5 Swimming pools - 4 Water Features - 5 Transformers Oil Type – 7 Generator - 18 Walk-in Fridges & Freezers - 200 Kitchen Esq. – 6 Outlets - 1. KM Beach - 98 Pumps, 150 Solar Panel, 19 Elevators & Laundry).

- Assist to Chief Engineer in process of Snagging of plants, machinery and Guest rooms as per Hilton Hotels standard
- Daily coordinate with project consultant and contractors for major product defects, Troubles and make sure the smooth project is going towards zero defects.
- Be a part of Testing and commissioning of Electrical panels, DG set, UPS, HVAC, WTP system, Gas fired boiler, calorifier Fire protection systems both Wet and Dry.
- Assist to Chief Engineer for getting government approval documents such as: RAK civil defense, HACCP, DM and etc.
- Recruitment of Engineering supervisors and Technicians according to budget
 Assist to Chief Engineer to get the quotations of plants and machinery comprehensive and Non-comprehensive AMC.
- Responsible for vendor development and purchasing management
- Responsible for the data collection and analysis of data leading up to preparation of the P&L and CapEx budget.

Hilton Resort & Spa

Shift Leader/Engineering Coordinator

Jan. 2011 – Oct. 2013 **Ras Al Khaimah, U.A.E**

Property of 475 Rooms including 151 Villa - 3 meeting Rooms - 8 Air cooled Chillers (319 Ton) - 32 AHU - 7 Swimming pools - 4 Water Features - 5 Transformers Oil Type - 4 Generator - 18 Walk-in Fridges & Freezers - 149 Kitchen Eqs. - 13 Outlets - 1.5 KM Beach - 89 Pumps & Laundry)

Worked on Projects:

- Pre-Opening of 723 rooms at **Doubletree by Hilton Resort & Spa**
- Laundry Extension Project at National Corporation for tourism and Hotels
- Pre-opening of 100 Villa's at Sandies Baobab Beach Resort
- Vellvett Club Extension Project at The Blowfish Group, Lagos, Nigeria
- Izanagi Japanize Restaurant Extension Project at The Blowfish Group, Lagos, Nigeria
- Woks Restaurant Renovation Project at The Blowfish Group, Lagos, Nigeria
- La-veranda Italian Restaurant Extension Project- at The Blowfish Group, Lagos, Nigeria
- The Fish Restaurant Project at The Blowfish Group, Lagos, Nigeria
- Pool Bar and pool renovation Project at The Blowfish Group, Lagos, Nigeria
- 40 Guest Rooms Renovation Projects- at The Blowfish Group, Lagos, Nigeria
- 100 room construction projects at The Blowfish Group, Lagos, Nigeria
- Dining room for 250 Pax Project at Pyramid Continental Hotel, Juba, South Sudan
- Ongoing Pyramid Mall and Apartments Projects at Pyramid Continental Hotel, Juba, South Sudan

Area of Expertise:

- Grounds maintenance
- RO and STP Plants
- Building Maintenance
- Energy Efficiency Program
- Preventive Maintenance Program
- Fire alarm & Fire Fighting maintenance •
- Pre-Opening Hotel/Resort

- Budgeting (R&M, P&L and POMEC) and forecasting
- Annual Maintenance Contract (AMC) performance
- Mechanical, Electrical and Plumbing Engineering (MEP)
- HVAC (water cooled chiller, Air cooled Chiller and VRV)
- BMS and CCTV installation & Maintenance
- Hotel/Resort's Construction and Renovation
- Diesel Generators (CAT, Perkins, Cummins) maintenance

Key Skills & Competencies:

- Communication and influencing
- Decision-making
- Commercial awareness

- Analytical and problem-solving skills
- The ability to lead and manage teams and projects
- Guest service
- Attention to detail but also the ability to see the implications for the bigger picture
- Organization, time management, prioritizing and the ability to handle a complex, varied workload
- A good knowledge of MS office,

Software Proficiencies:

- AutoCAD 2010
- Webpro
- Birchstreet
- HotSOS
- BMS (Building Management System)

- Maximo
- Edocs
- Outlook
- CMMS
- MS office Suite

Education:

• Bachelor's Degree in Mechanical Engineering-2010 (Attested)

National Institute of Engineering & Technology (NIET), New Delhi

• Diploma in System & Networking-2009

NIIT Institute, New Delhi

• 10+2 in Math Science -2006

Shaheed Madhuban Karamad Inter college, Deoria, U.P.

Certifications:

- First Aider Certificate by First Aid International. Ref: 160564/509550/665072
- HACCP Certificate By: Food Safety Training Solutions. Ref: 2981
- Fire & Life Safety Training Certificate By: RAK Civil Defense
- Train the trainer By **Hilton**
- Performance Management Training by **Hilton**
- Completed over 50 Trainings and certifications within **Hilton University**

Recognized and Awards

- Employee of The Month Award -7 times (2011-2016)
- Employee of the Year -2016

References:

- Axel Hauser General Manager
- Axel.Hauser@pyramidcontinentalhotel.com
- Mob: +211924013028
- Praveen Kumar Sharma- Chief Engineer
- P.sharma@assets-intel.com
- Mob: +971503637322
- Saad Youssef- Director of Operation
- <u>Saad.Youssef@theblowfishhotel.com</u>
- Mob: +2347080070275